доброе утро всем, это Muhammad Ali
с новым видео и
в этом видео Я хочу поделиться с вами
как правильно настроить шасси
с момента как вы его получили
Я поробую сделать это настолько просто
насколько возможно, особенно для новичков
так же надеюсь это поможет с вашими
текущими настройками
так давайте начнем
многие знакомы с ситуацией когда
вы получили вашу новую шасси
которая, скорее всего, у вас первая
если вы конечно начинающий и вы
получаете тысячи кусочков, которые
собираете вместе и пытаетесь катать
первый раз и реальность догоняет вас
это далеко не то, что вы ожидали
будьте честны с собой, вы купили
шасси по видео с
YouTube и Facebook, что, по моему
мнению, плохая идея
это фаза один
вторая фаза, Я называю ее
фазой скорби
в этот момент вы расстроены
Вы злитесь и жалеете, что потратили
200+ долларов на
ЭТОТ кусок мусора
и это вполне нормальная ситуация
все начинают примерно так же
есть кое-что, что вам нужно знать
для получения удовольствия от свое шасси
надо пройти много шагов
о которых новички не знают
потому что в инструкции этого нету
и Я докажу это, поделившись своим
опытом и надеюсь это повысит
Вашу мотивацию продолжить с шасси
Я начал дрифтить
в сентябре 2019 года, моей первой шасси
была DRZ 1
и до этого Я уаствовал в соревнования
багги в масштабах 1/8 и 1/10
электро и нитро и после этого Я
гонял на дронах почти 4 года
так что Я имею опыт
когда дело доходит
до сборки и тюнинга
когда Я получил DRZ, это была моя первая
мини дрифт шасси
я собрал ее и когда попробовал
впервый раз, я смотрелся как
5ти летний пацан с пультом
серьёзно, так что это нормально, потому что
даже имея опыт сборки и
настойки, в этот момент
мой опыт сборки был
не терять сцепление с дорогой
в гонках, если вы скользите боком или
теряете сцепление, вы теряете время
и если вы теряете время
вы проигрываете гонку
Я пересобирал мою DRZ 16 раз
ровно 16 раз, что бы она вела себя
как надо, потому то в голове
я все думал как
участвовать в гонках
и думал, что проблема в шасси, так что
Я посмотрел много видео и прочитал
много обзоров
и в конце Я собрал все части правильно
рычаги двигались свободно
без намека на люфт
как и должно быть и Я пробовал
каждый день и был прогресс
но не так быстро
или впечатляюще как я видел
на YouTube, так что я позвал своего приятеля
потому что я подумал
может проблема не в машине
а во мне
я повзонил приятеля и он про
дрифтер 1/10 масштаба Я имеб ввиду, что
он из тех, кто берет свою машину и
едет в аэропорт, что бы учавствовать в
соревнования в Японии
в дрифт эвентах в UK, так что я позвонил ему
и пригласил в гости
он понятия не имел, что его ожидает
thing he said is this amenity that all
Hino I told him now I tried to explain
that DRZ what's that so he told me okay
let's try I gave him the radio it took
может быть 30 секунд он крутился на право
и на лево 48 секнуд и потом он пол минуты
держал угол
Я даже не думал
и не занл, что шасси
так может, так что он подтвердил
мои опасения, что проблема не в
шасси и вы должны всегда помнить
об этом
так что если вы начинающий Я ожидаю, что
Вы сталкнетесь с теме же проблемами
что и Я
с моими первыми пробами DRZ 1
Если вы конечно считаете
что дрифт это просто скользить туда-сюда
то у вас получится сразу
У меня получилось скользить
с первого раза, но
проблема была в том, что это было не так
ровно и плавно как я ожидал
Когда я держал пульт в первый раз
я свпоминал те ролики
и угла которые парни
держали и ту плавность с которой
они управляли шасси, но
на тот момент я так не мог
или моя сборка была
достойна пяти летнего ребенка
на этом этапе, если бы у вас был
опыт в дрифте, вы бы
знали, что с вашей шасси не так
и исправили это без проблем
Но если вы начинающий
единственный путь продолжить после так
ситуации, это понять концептуальные
основы дрифта, так что когда мы
говорим дрифт, идея состояит в потере
сцепления, но при этом мы сохраняем
полный контроль движения
так, если зад шасси закручивается
ваша рулевая
должна компенсировать
любой угол который вы держите
даже если это 90 градусов, это основной
концепт дрифта. Если у вас много газа и
меньше выворота или
наоборот, шасси сразу же закртит
Давайте начнем обсуждать как заставить
вашу шасси вести себя правильно и вот мои
три основных шага
которым вы должны следовать
первый шаг, сборка
потом настройки и навыки дрифта, если вы
собрали и настроили правильно
ваш навык будет расти очень быстро
но если вы запутались в первых двух шагах
вы либо сдадитесь и
возможно продадите шасси или
вы не будете видеть пргресса
your skills so you have to follow the
steps so building that sounds simple
right you just download the instruction
manual
you read through it and you follow it
step by step which part goes where
and you're done with it this is not
necessary means you build your chassis
there's a big difference between a Lego
and an RC drift car for example
let's talk about this arm here
for example if not discount necessary
any car if the manual says put the arm
in this position and place two or three
shims up front for example if you don't
know what the shim is it's a small
plastic spacers that you have to place
to move the arm in a certain position
forward and back or backward to control
your Caster anyway for example let's say
the the manual set two two shims and you
place the two Shams and then your arm
acts like this see
this is bad this is too much play in the
arm and the reason for that even the
manual sit so because the the quality
control for this small plastic injection
mold part is not 100 accurate my arm
might be
0.05 thinner than your arm so in my case
I have to place one extra shim here to
control or to eliminate display while at
the same time maintaining full up and
low pre-motion so these things you have
to consider this is the difference
between
putting together a chassis and building
a chassis and this goes all over the
chassis all parts should fit nicely in
the sense they move freely but with zero
play
is the enemy of drifting keep in mind
always play is the enemy with drifting
if you have any play in your
steering
or in your arms or in your wheels
this will drive your gyro crazy your car
will be twerking all over the place so
this thing to keep in mind now there are
some rare situations where we have to
choose between either having a little
bit of play or a little bit of friction
for example let's say you're placing
your knuckle or your your arm and if you
place for example two shims it's a
little bit loose but if you place
another shim it's tight so in that
situation you have to improvise you have
to take that extra shim and sand it down
then keep at it try again until you lose
the play while maintaining a free motion
of the arm so the first thing that I do
when it comes to tuning the first thing
I adjust is my right height and if you
don't know what right height is it's a
bit simply the distance or the clearance
between the bottom of your chassis and
the ground I noticed that most guys run
2.2 or 2.3 I don't remember I think 2.3
millimeter up front and 2.5 millimeter
in the back so basically the chassis is
slightly leaning forward
yeah so it's slightly leaning forward
now for me and this is highly subjective
to your uh driving skill and what you
prefer when it comes to weight
distribution because the whole idea of
having right height tilted forward or
leaning backward is weight distribution
after all now for me when I do my right
height
I consider two things the first thing is
the overall weight of my chassis and the
strength of my Springs
and my goal the thing I want to achieve
is on acceleration I want my chassis to
squat little bit to the back
okay when I press acceleration the
chassis should slightly
lean to the back like this
is the same concept that we use in 110
two-wheel drive indoor buggies because
since it's a three wheel drive the more
leaning or the more weight shifting to
the back that means the more weight will
be on the rear wheel which are the
active wheel connected motor and this
way you will maintain constant Traction
in the back and constant forward motion
for example if I if my Springs were hard
my rear springs were hard and won't
acceleration nothing change if I crease
acceleration the car slightly move in
the same right height I mean the shift
there's no shift at all because the
strings are hard in that case I
deliberately screw in my rear
droop screws slightly so my right height
would look like this standing still
because I know there's no weight shift
on acceleration because the Springs are
hard in case if my Springs are soft
and when I press acceleration I notice
that the body automatically leans to the
back in that case I set up my right
height to be parallel to the ground and
my preferred spot is about 2.5
millimeter all across
if I have to lean it to the back via
group screws I go three millimeters up
front and I go about 2.5 millimeters in
the rear and if you notice this chassis
now as it is it's slightly leaning to
the back
you can see the clearance here how big
it is
and here slightly smaller and if you
notice here also my drip screws are not
identical I did this deliberately to
show you if you noticed the the toe bar
here is not parallel to the ground so
my right group screw on the right side
here is shorter than the other I have to
screw this side slightly bit in to push
the chassis slightly down
this way
it's parallel to the ground so if I
release it you can notice my chassis is
tilted to the left side and this one of
the features that most guys don't pay
attention to and then at this setting if
I drive my car it will ride well but
because my chest is all tilted to this
side it will not be consistent when it
comes to Drifting then after I'm done
with my ride height the next thing that
I adjust is my track width and the check
width simply is the distance
between the center of your chassis and
the outer surface of your wheels it can
go either narrow or wide and this
depends on two factors of course the
main factor is your body
what type of body have do you have a
narrow body or wide body and the second
factor is the offset of your wheels okay
so basically you measure your body and
you try to mimic that on your chassis
for example if you have a narrow uh
chassis like the the XR is actually a
white dressing if you have I mean if you
have a low offset Tire
you have to undo your screws on the arms
the upper arms and the low arms so the
whole assembly goes outward and you
imagine measure the distance between the
wheels and try to mimic it or try to get
the same distance of your body and the
goal
is to have your wheels that flat with
your fenders see in the rear in the rear
if I if I go beyond my fenders on
acceleration since my body already
squats it will drop against the tire and
you will lose speed up front if you go
beyond your fenders on steering the
wheels will grab or will drop against
your Fender and will spin out
immediately
in the rear most of most of the cars in
the market right now there's no
adjustability for the width
at stock form you have to buy extra
parts and the mode and the extra part
that I'm talking about is the the rear
lower arm example for the xrx there are
two options you can go with the big with
the long uh lower arm lower rear arm or
there's an optional part which the lower
ear arm has a screw in it and it's
expandable itself you can adjust it up
and down but at the same time you have
to accumulate for the extra width so you
have to purchase the optional dog bone
which is I think 10.3 millimeter let's
document it for the extra width of your
chassis after you're done setting up
your trackpad the next step or for me
the next step that I go through
immediately is my Caster setting now if
you don't know what Caster is it's
simply the axis of rotation in your
front wheel so imagine if this is the
axis of rotation at this sitting when I
rotate my front wheel it will rotate
fourth and back around this axis now if
I adjust my Caster if I adjust this
angle slightly to the back the wheel
will rotate slightly down and up and if
I adjust more again down and up and
that's what explains uh what a lot of
players or Drifters are suffering from
it's called wheel lifting that means you
have too much Caster to the point that
one wheel is pushing against the angle
and lifting the other wheel of the
ground the front wheel of course now the
theory or or there is a forecaster or
the function of Caster is
something called or we call it in
drifting what we call it the coin effect
or the Frisbee effect imagine
if you are rotating your wheels
now this Caster let me get the max
Caster so you can see
now I have the max caster
when I'm at full lock you'll notice this
wheel
is tilted to the back and this is what
gives you the Frisbee effect or the coin
effect imagine if you throw a frisbee on
the ground or a coin on the ground the
coin will go in straight line until it
starts losing speed and then whatever
angle the coin is leaning at it will
start rotating toward that angle
until it reach the center lose speed and
then drop it's just low of Gravity by
Isaac Newton so this effect is very
important this is the most important
effect when it comes to adjusting not
adjusting when it comes to stabilizing
your drifting angle
let's put it to practice for example you
are drifting on this direction you're
rotating now your rear end is already at
higher speed so it's it's standing or
it's going to
spin forward what you do is you counter
act that you counter steel right
to catch your it from spinning out but
at the same time because you have too
much Caster this wheel is digging in
that direction meaning this wheel has
the tendency to rotate on that direction
as if your front wheel is digging on the
ground pushing your front to the
direction of your drift and preventing
you from spinning out
the way to adjust your Caster is
different from chassis to chassis some
chassis like the DK have Caster screw
you undo the screw then you are free to
push forth or back your upper arms front
upper arms to adjust your casters most
of the other chassis use shims if you
take a look here in your upper arm you
have a dead space that you have to place
cm in to prevent the extra play and at
the same time to adjust your Caster if
you plus your shims up front you push
the arm to the back so you get more
caster and vice versa and all the space
in between you can divide like shame in
front and shame in the back some other
chest is just like uh yes the the GLD
they have Caster block which is optional
this block you unscrew the two blocks
the two screws and you slide the whole
block forward and back if you have a GLD
you have to get the Caster block
otherwise it will not perform right
so at this point I I know what you're
thinking about how much he has a share
you should I use and it's a hard
question to answer because it's
subjective it depends on your driving
skills it depends on the surface you're
running on the type of tires and that
the type of chassis that you have and
the overall weight over the chassis that
you got on uh for me the way I do it uh
initially I start with Max caster and I
try it out if I don't have wheel lift I
stay at Max faster but if I start to see
we'll lift as if I'm driving a three
wheeler instead of four wheel contact I
reduce the Caster Some people prefer not
to reduce the Caster but to screw in the
front Loop screw meaning to reduce the
front right height and it's up to you
but initially start with Max caster and
test it the only side effect to Max
Caster is wheel lifting now after you're
done testing various angles of caster
and eventually finding what Suits You
me I go immediately after that to my
camera setting and if you don't if you
don't know what camber is basically it's
the vertical relationship between your
wheels and the body so if my wheels is
straight parallel to my body it's called
zero camber now if my wheels start to
lean toward the body this is positive
camber
and the opposite direction is negative
rule of thumb never use negative camber
your wheels should be either straight
to your body parallel to your body or
leading to all your body the only
situation where negative camber is
acceptable is in your front leading
wheel for example at full lock you can
see my front leading wheel here has a
negative camber
now the way I do it is at the beginning
I start with zero all around all my
wheels I place them or I adjust them to
be vertical or parallel to my body then
I test drive my assessing the whole
concept of camber is to gain traction or
to lose traction see at vertical sitting
that means your tire is maintaining full
patch contact that means your tire is at
highest grip state or this is the
grippiest contact or the grippiest uh
Jackson you can get from your tires now
if I go just drive my car and I find it
that it's hard to lose traction to
initiate your drift I meaning I have to
really hit my throttle just to get my
rear end to swing that means I have too
much traction in the back so I start by
adding more camber slightly then I test
drive and then add a test drive and so
on until I feel comfortable with my
chassis I I became Miami until you get
to the point that it's predictable and
easy to initiate your drift and then you
stay at that angle regardless of what
angle 0 1 2 3 usually we don't go beyond
three three degrees camber
but that's how I do it for the rear now
in the front it's little bit different
because the point of camber in the front
not only traction but traction during
rotation during full lock and the way I
do it is I try
to achieve
maximum contact during full lock
in one of five wheels at least so in
case
let's see the xrx
for example here
at full lock you can see I managed to
get full contact on my leading wheel my
trailing wheel slightly lifting off the
ground it has positive camber but my
leading wheel almost almost has zero
camber and the way to to visualize it or
to to say that you have that is by
holding your chassis against a flat
surface like this and you can see I have
full contact here and if you can see in
the back there there's a point contact
so this tire maintains full grip at full
lock and this is what controls my
direction of motion
now after you finish your camber the
next step for me is to set up my toe if
you don't know what toe is it's the
relationship between each wheel the
front together and the rear together so
for example if my wheels are parallel to
each other this is called a zero tall
if they started to lean toward each
other from the front it's called
positive tool and it goes the opposite
direction it's called negative two now
in the rear you have the option of
running either parallel which is zero or
you can run positive one degree two
degree Three Degree up to you and the
front you have extra options you can run
it either zero
you can run it negative meaning leaning
to it sorry a positive meaning leaning
toward each other or you can run it
negative pointing away from each other
let's talk about the video first what's
the the functionality of of the toe and
there's a debate when it comes to the
rear uh most guys in in the 110
Community they prefer to run parallel
and some of them prefer to run toe n and
the the concept behind that for example
let's say you started to initiate your
drift
to the side to the right side now your
rear end is already swinging and at the
same time you're counter steering to
catch your rear end from
spinning beyond your front wheel and
spinning out so at this point
this end is going front and if your real
rear tires that give me something
straight let's say this is the direction
of your rear tires they're pointing this
way if you rear tires at this position
it's easier for you to spin out but if
you're leading
rear wheel is slightly toe and meaning
pushing to that direction
let me get the camera right sorry
if you're real a real leading wheel this
wheel which are we are drifting on this
direction if this wheel is not pointing
straight but slightly leaning inward to
end that means this wheel will counter
at the action of the spin so it will
stabilize your rear end from spinning
out and it will make it easier for you
to hold your drift without spinning out
to me I prefer to have my rear toes set
to 3
3 but it's different from player to
player so I start in every chassis with
zero and I tried the slide I add add
more angles more to n until I feel
comfortable and you should do the same
this is for the year now for the front
you have
different angle you can go to n zero or
toe out and that the idea behind that in
the front is not just to counteract the
direct angle is to
shape your steering geometry the way you
like it for example if I have
let me get another chassis easier to
show for example the trz
if I have for example here if you see a
half slightly negative toe negative
minus one actually so the reason for
that if I have negative 2 during full
lock
I will get something called parallel
Ackerman we'll talk about that later
meaning at full lock my two wheels are
parallel to each other at this Angle now
if I have for example if I don't have
this just you know if I have two out
which I don't like I never used to I
would have to out at the front when I
turn at full lock
your
leading wheel will be almost 90 degree
more than this it will be almost like
this
but your training wheel would be off
slightly less angle that you're leading
wheel now and if you have it zero it
will most likely be the same the way I
do it I usually go for either parallel
or zero sorry uh one degree two n so I
can get Federal acronym at each angle
now if you notice here
you can see my wheel is rubbing I guess
the shot this is not my steering
geometry this is not the angle because
you're not keeping in mind the weight of
the body and the electronics
so at full when I when I place it on the
ground it will look like this it will
still spin freely and that one thing you
have to consider also sometimes you go
with negative to a front your tire
trailing Tire will will turn so much to
the point that it drops against the
shock so if you have that problem either
you have to increase your width or you
have to go with a bigger offset wheel or
you have to lower your right height
for example this is the right high C if
I lower the right height the whole
steering geometry will change
and at this point
my tire doesn't even go that far but if
I drop it down the tire will go far to
the point that it contacts
after I'm done with my toe sitting I
immediately start adjusting my agreement
and by far this is the step where I
spend most of my time at when it comes
to tuning my sensing I experiment until
I find with suits me of course and
everybody should do the same and if you
are unable to hold your sliding angles
for long duration of time then most
probably your acne needs more work and
if you don't know what Ackerman is it's
the relationship between your front
wheel throughout the range of motion now
at neutral position you can see that you
either have zero toe or two n or two out
correct now during your motion when you
turn your radio or your wheels the
relationship between those two wheels
it's called Ackerman
now when it comes to Ackerman you have
three options that you can run your
chassis option number one is positive
Acumen which means at foot lock
your leading wheel has more steering
lock than your trailing wheel just like
this and most of drifters run this
option it makes sense because this is
the option at which your car is most
Nimble at meaning at this option you
have the ability or ease of switching
from side to side in case if you have a
course with a lot of turns and angles so
this is option number one option number
two is to run a parallel Ackerman which
means that your wheels at full lock are
parallel to each other
and this is the option that you should
run if you have a course which has list
tracks oh sorry listeners but long
sweeping angles so you have you want to
have the ability to hold your angle for
a long duration of time this is the best
option for you also if you want to grab
walk this is the best option for you and
there's the last option which is a
reverse acronym or known as negative
acronym also which means the opposite
your leading wheel has more angle lock
than your trailing wheel and this is the
easiest setup to crap up
from the beginning if you have no
experience with the cap walking this is
the easiest setup to grab work but keep
in mind because this angle is different
than this angle they will fight each
other and you will lose speed you'll be
able to carpool that slowly and if you
have a small track it's not a big
problem but for longer track you will
hold the whole traffic behind you now
here where it gets a little bit
confusing before you go on and start
adjusting your Ackerman you need to know
that Ackerman adjustment is sensitive to
six factors
the first factor is your steering
assembly
then your track width your right height
your toe your caster and the level the
vertical distance or the vertical
difference between your steering
assembly and your knuckles
so steering system what does that mean
or a steering assembly simply it means
the way that your Servo is connected to
your front wheels and as of now there
are three systems in the market the
first one which is my favorite it's the
direct connection meaning your wheels
are connected via VIA your steering
links directly to your Servo horn a
t-shaped Servo horn this is number one
number two there's something called
sliding rack either curved sliding Rack
or flat or straight sliding rack and in
this situation you have your Servo with
your Servo horn connected to a metal bar
this bar is sandwiched between ball
bearing and then it connects to your
steering links to your wheels
like the this is the GLD same system as
the xrx also same principle same concept
and the flat steering rack is like the
Geo the B embracing Dr Z1 there is a
rack seems similar to the drg and xrx RX
but it's a flat track straight rack same
concept and then the third option
available in the market right now it's
called buildcrank it's a t-shaped plate
which are screwed which is screwed over
your body the base plate of your body uh
via ball bearing
and then on each side it's connected up
front to your steering link to your
wheels and in the middle it has a ball
ball link which connects your Servo horn
just like this
it's called buildcrank
and this is this is four wheel drive AMZ
and this system is the system that I
least like actually I hate the system
because it it has a tendency for
vertical movement or vertical wiggling
in your steering link itself
unlike
the ball bearing sliding rack the rack
is already sandwiched between ball
bearings so there's no movement other
than side to side very very stable and
uh
this system in my opinion in the market
is the direct connection because direct
connection system allows the designer to
have a sliding Servo Mount which simply
will adjust your agreement without any
headache now the second factor to
consider when you are adjusting your
Ackerman is your front track width now
if you are planning to run a positive
Ackerman you have no problem you're
attracted you can run any any width you
want and you will get positive Ackerman
with no issues but if you are planning
to go for a parallel agreement or
reverse acronym negative Ackerman then
you should your trackpad will come to
play in the sense for example
this is white setting even then if you
can see here my wheel is dropping
against the shock so in that case you
have to run a wider frontal track width
so as you can get clearance at full lock
without your wheel rubbing the shock if
you restart rubbing the shock
immediately it will push this wheel into
a halt and you will spin out immediately
the third factor to consider is the
right height
now for example this car is tuned
perfectly parallel Ackerman okay and if
you take a look here
you'll notice this this wheel the
leading the trailing wheel is already
rubbing against the shock because this
is not my right height you have to
consider your electronics I mean in that
case my battery and my body which will
in turn push the front little bit so
let's see now it's rubbing
a little bit pressure
this will be easier
you hear now it's rubbing with why apply
a little bit pressure see what happens
this is my right height so at full lock
I have no problem with my tire rubbing
against the shock
now the fourth factor that comes into
play is your tone which means your
steering links length themselves before
the steps before I started this step
usually I just install my wheels with no
steering links and I cannot rotate them
forth and back to see if I have an issue
clearing my shock in my trailing wheel
or creating my lower body plate in my
leading wheel after that I pre-measured
the distance between the ball link of
the knuckle and the steering assembly
mimic that into my steering legs itself
and install them to to check the
clearance if it works or not and usually
if you have your link sitting at the toe
out in neutral position that means you
will get a positive agreement at full
lock like this and if you have your toe
zero just like my car here slightly
actually it's a positive slight positive
but because this is not my setup my
setup
when I squat my car a little bit more
likely close to parallel so that's the
thing at full lock
I'll get better agreement and if you go
the opposite direction which is toe and
at neutral
that means you'll get reverse acronym
meaning your
your trading wheel will be at more angle
than your leading wheel
now the fifth factor that can affect
your Ackerman setup is your Caster value
and what I mean by that is the
horizontal relationship means fourth or
back the relationship between your
steering assembly and your knuckle this
is the xrx take a look at the ball Link
at the steering assembly here and the
ball Link at the knuckle you can see
they're almost at the same angle or
parallel to each other at same line
now if this ball link
at the knuckle we're positioned a little
bit back
or a little bit fourth the whole
Ackerman geometry will change for
example let's take a car that has an an
easy Caster adjustment yes yeah the GLD
for example take a look at my toe at
maximum Caster keep in mind the steering
link has not changed I did not play with
my steer link but I increased my Caster
so at this position I have a 12. now if
I decrease my Caster watch my wheels
my toe will change
let's take something more clear for
example
the DK
same concept if I go Max caster
watch my toe
see the difference
and again
the trc2
this is the Caster screw for the trc2 if
I change my Caster take a look at my toe
so when you change your Caster your toe
will change at neutral position which
means it will change your accurate at
full lock
now the last factor to look out for when
you adjusting your Ackerman is the
vertical relationship between your
steering assembly and your knuckle and
what I mean by that is take a look at
the Bold link
at my steering assembly and the bone
Link at my knuckle see the difference in
level if this level change say to this
point if I push my arm a little bit
higher if this level change
it will affect my Ackerman and the way
to see this is to place your chassis at
a flat surface
and now take a look at my trailing wheel
the down wheel here if I reduce my right
height meaning I pushed my front car
down see what happens to my trailing
wheel
that's why before I start anything any
adjustment at all in my chassis the
first thing I set is my right height
another question I get a lot of times
regarding
stealing geometry is why do I bend my
steering links or when should you do it
if you have a car
that has a fixed Servo Mount and you are
running a front wide track and at the
same time you want to have a parallel
Ackerman without sacrificing your
maximum steering lock this is the
situation where you need to bend your
steering links for example let's take a
look at this the BM bracing DRZ for
example imagine if I'm let me get
something pointy
imagine if I'm running a straight
standard straight steering links at
certain point
the link itself because it's straight it
will Jam against the knuckle so this is
the maximum steering if I am if I was
running a straight steel link because at
this point the ceiling link again it
will rub and jam against your knuckle
itself so to get the maximum Ackerman or
parallel Ackerman at this setting I will
have to run my
leading wheel at this position so this
will be my maximum steering lock with
straight steering Link at parallel
Ackerman which is still good still
impressive and it will perform well but
what if I want to run maximum
lock with parallel Ackerman at this
point to clear this point
of the knuckle I need to bend it in a
way
the steering link will wrap around the
knuckle without rubbing like this
after I'm done with my tuning I install
my electronics for the first time
my ESC my Servo my gyro everything with
the battery on then I mount my body
after I mount my body then I start
adjusting my suspension what we mean by
suspicion is your
shock itself the shock position either
vertical or horizontal and the type of
spring that you'll use medium soft or
hard and it all depends on you generally
speaking the softer suspension will give
you more traction more Tire grip the
harder suspension will give you less
traction less tire grip and if you are
planning to go for a maximum body roll
then you need to have a vertical
position shocks so a vertical position
shock it's the position at which the
shock is easier to compress the more
angular shock you'll have the more
resistant to Vertical compress generally
speaking even in one tip
and if you want to buy the roll I don't
like Body Rolls but if you want to body
roll you need to have your Springs soft
your shocks at vertical position and you
need to mount the most weight at the top
plate ESC battery everything if you can
mount everything at the top plate so you
have a high CG High center of gravity
this way when you turn in an angle the
higher position of your weight
at combined with the softer spring and
the vertical position of your shocks it
will allow your body to lean on one side
than the other side and yet if you want
to have a more effect of body roll you
need monoshocks just like this of course
you need it both front and rear
and you can see the effect right away if
I press here the car the chassis Will
Roll to the other side
initially this is the the Monoshock that
I got for my xrx I use it with my xrx
initially and because
I'm using a heavy Die Cast body for my
exercise I don't want to change this
body it's too much the roll is too much
to the point that when I steer at one
angle I feel that my chassis is dragging
to that angle it's impressive impressive
on video but it's it's not a good
feeling on the radio
so at this point I'm done with my
initial tuning and then I start the
process of fine tuning which takes at
least one month for me to fine tune one
car and the reason for that is even
though my car is set up
at this
level
I don't know exactly how it will handle
on the track so I drive it for few days
and then I start making small adjustment
when I say a small adjustment mean I
will change one thing at a time and test
drive it for at least three battery
packs then make the adjustment another
adjustment and three packs and so on the
reason for that is whenever you make an
adjustment initially it will feel weird
to you the control will feel off not
because the adjustment is bad because
you are not used to it so you have to
give your time you give yourself time
between each adjustment to just to see
if you can adapt to this adjustment if
you can if you can get the right muscle
memory down to control the car at that
sitting and then move to the next
adjustments so it takes time at least a
month for me to to fine tune my car to
be exactly or to to just exactly the way
I like it and there's nothing more
satisfying in this hobby besides
building the car which is fun after
building the car there's nothing more
satisfying in this hobby than to get
your car to drive exactly the way you
want it
electronic wise when it comes to soft or
smooth drifting the most important
things to me are the servo and the
motoring ESC combo Circle you need to
have a good Servo not mediocre a good
Servo don't scam up on your Servo it's
very important
yes sorry gyro wise any mediocre child
will do for me because the function of
the gyro is to assist you not to drive
the car and to me I use all my Gyros at
40 to 50 Max I feel that when I try it
at 70 or 80 percent not because not not
just it will start to Jitter I feel that
it it starts to fight me when I'm
driving I feel that I'm fighting the car
the general is over correcting me when I
don't want any correction it prevents me
from holding uh large angles so I don't
like that feeling this is regarding the
gyro and I always face my gyro at lower
position if possible in all my cars my
gyro is always at the bottom
like so always at the bottom here
Electronics
it's better if you have the money to go
straight for censored system this is the
smooth smooth system that you can get
with a low power because drifting most
fuel drifting is at lower power but it's
not
important per se if you are tight on
budget you can still go for a sensorless
system and with little bit of tweaking
get a smoother acceleration at lower
speed and the way I do it of course you
have three factors that come into
consideration your motor itself
your sensorless ESC
and your radio first of all your motor
and before I start some of you might be
wondering I already have a sensorless
system and it's smooth as butter right
of course and most likely that's the
case because you've never tried a
censored system before imagine the
difference or how can I explain it to
you imagine you have a real car
a driven car not a man not an automatic
car stick driven car but it's missing
the first gear
try to roll that car from zero to
Rolling and from Total desktop try to
roll that car without using the first
gear you will be able to roll it but
initially it will be a small kick or
you'll feel a small jerk before the car
start rolling the same thing goes with
sensorless system
even if you are very sensitive or very
gentle with your trigger finger
initially of course first you will have
slight dead band a range of motion that
nothing happening then once you engage
your motor you will first hear some
clicking sounds and then after that the
car will slightly jump then start
rolling with sensorless with the
sensored system you don't have that from
zero there's no dead band and smoothly
from zero till full
speed the car will go at consistent
acceleration and that's what we are
trying to achieve with sensorless system
so the way to go about this first of
course your your motor itself if you are
a beginner get 3500 KB motor 3500 KB
motor is a high torque low speed motor
remember this is not a razor speed is
not the goal here what we aiming for is
the smoothness of your slide and overall
style and in that case torque is more
important to you than speed so this is
regarding the KV and now if you have any
previous experience with drifting or are
seeing in general it's better to go for
something between 5000 to 7000 KV this
is the sweet spot for me anyway now
after you chose your your KV your
appropriate KV motor for your skill the
second thing is to go for your opinion
which is the blue gear that we have here
now general rule
if you have a small opinion
you will have a faster initial
acceleration but lower top speed and if
you have a bigger pinion gear you will
have initial low acceleration but faster
top speed if that makes any sense and
just to build it in action for example
if you have two cars say the car on the
right have 15 to spin in and the car on
the left have for example 25 pinion if
we start racing initially the car on the
right will take off but with time the
car on the left will catch up and go
beyond the current lift if that makes
any sense so using that concept into
your advantage and especially if you are
running a sensorless system the first
week that you can do to get a smoother
acceleration out of your motor is to
Gear Up
usually most of the cars in the market
they come with a size 14 15 or 16
toothpine what I personally do is I
always go above the standard by five to
six tips meaning for example the xrx the
advice to use 15. my smallest gear I
have is 21 and I have another gear 25 25
is smoother than 21 for me at least and
I know what you're thinking wait a
minute gearing up will cause heating
issues to my to my car and you're
correct if you are running a buggy a
troggy on-road racing car anything that
has rubber tires that maintain constant
grip to the ground and you Gear Up you
most likely will end up either frying
your ESC or demagnetizing your motor but
remember these small things are sliders
they wait very little and they run on
plastic wheels that has minimal traction
and in all my cars I've never
experienced any heating issues for
example I told you this one I run it
I'll run it I will show some videos
running 25 life to see the smoothness of
it of it and with 25 no hitting shoe for
example the DK
comes with this pinion
16th opinion and I run it with 27 tooth
pinion
and there's no heating issue this one is
smooth don't get me wrong it's smooth
it's good this one feels like you're
gliding on Ice that's the difference
between the two after gearing the second
factor that will affect your smoothness
is your ESC itself always try to get a
programmable the ESC something that will
accept a Programming Card that you can
use to adjust your values and the most
important value is something called
Punch If you don't know what punch is
it's the initial current sent from your
ESC to your motor to get the lowest
possible speed of rotation and the way I
do it I always in all my car I use punch
one meaning when I engage my trigger the
initial power sent is just enough to get
my car to roll keep in mind some bad
sensorless sorry specialist motors with
punch one you might feel a little bit of
Jitter or twitch if you have such motor
then increase your value a little bit go
for two or three but always stay at a
lower punch value the last thing that
you can do to get a smoother
acceleration out of your sensorless
system is by adjusting your radio itself
now the throttle or the acceleration
which is the relation between your
trigger finger and your and your motor
is linear meaning for example if I move
my trigger by the value of 1 the motor
will spin at the value funnel speed wise
and if I go for two it will go at speed
of 2 3 speed of 3 and so on so the
relation between them are linear what I
want to do is for example I want to
press the value of 1 but I want my car
to move at the value of 0.5 or 0.6 less
then speed wise this than my trigger
finger and this is something called
negative throttle curve for example
let's take a look here I'm not sure if
this is going to pick up correctly
this is no this is the DRZ
xrx
go to throttle
better lock here
for example go to throttle
see here it says curve for example now
you see the curve the standard curve
looks like this it's the linear I press
one it moves at speed of one and so on
what I have is negative 45 throttle
curve negative meaning when I press the
acceleration initially the call will
move at small at slower speed until it
reached the point of 50 percent halfway
through the throttle after that it will
shoot up another way to look at it is uh
the first 50 of my throttle is my
playing range the range which I drift
most of at most of the time at and the
second half is my turbo boost when I go
to the second half the engine will rev
at higher speed full speed in that case
here I'm if I'm using for example this
is 6000 KB right so the first 50 of my
throttle link the the motor only produce
3000 worth of KV
and the second half if I press full
acceleration it will unlock the full
potential of the motor to full speed and
this way I have a better control over my
lower speed
now after you finish building and tuning
your car we come to the third step which
is the most important thing is your
drifting skills this is the time the
point of time at which your car is
somewhat predictable to you and when it
comes to control and it's up to you to
take it to the next level with your
drifting skills I've seen a lot of
videos of if some of you guys are doing
donuts donuts will get you nowhere
always try to drift around fixed objects
start with a DOT or a cup anything
that's fixed to the ground and try
[Music]
spin around it while maintaining a
constant distance from it this is number
one then go to two dots then three dots
then after that create small a track the
point here is not just to slide the
point here is to be predictable with
your sliding action to be in total
control of your motion and I've seen a
lot of guys also um
paying or paying more attention to the
aesthetic of their car like the body the
wheels and everything
if your car does not ride well and slide
well does it really matter how it looks
this is for my perspective I've been in
this hobby for almost now a year and the
most expensive body I have is this one
forty dollars all other bodies I have
either twenty twenty five dollars
because most of my time I spend it on
tuning and building and getting my my
drifting skills and my 20 skills to be
right so let's uh put what what all what
we talked about into practice I chose to
go for the xrx for the demonstration
because I noticed most of you guys are
picking this chassis up these days and
understandably why it's one of my
favorites so what I have here is the
cheapest form of the xrx the full
plastic form except for three parts uh I
have the adjustable wheelbase
plates and I have the alloy shop towers
and I have the rear toe block these are
the three things that I purchased extra
other than that it's the cheapest one
the base the base model so regarding the
adjustable wheelbase I remove I run this
usually at 102 millimeter with my Die
Cast body but for this demonstration I
shrunked it down back to 94 millimeters
so if you if you don't have adjustable
wheelbase this is the dimension that
you're gonna get the same with our
wheelbase of this same shape of this the
second thing is the shock towers and
this is um this is an Integrity upgrade
rather than performance upgrade the only
thing that I hate about the xrx is that
shop Tower which is even though it's
carbon fiber it's very thin when you
scroll in your rear mounting screws
you'll immediately notice that the tower
itself will bow in and with time it can
crack it did not crack on me but I did
not wait for it I immediately went it
for the alloy shock Towers the other
thing is when you install the alloy
shock Towers it's considerably thicker
than the standard so what happened is if
you run your
shocks in the correct position meaning
the the tension ring up top it will
catch against the shock itself and it
will Jam the smooth it will Jam the the
arm itself it will not the shock will
not function smoothly so if you have
this you have to reverse
your shocks keep the Rings the tension
rings at the bottom rear and front so
this is the second thing I did the the
other thing I did is usually I run this
car wide wider than this I undo the the
links the upper and lower links to get a
wider width track width but I went for
stock this is the stock as the manual
says and I run curved steering links
again I went with stock steering legs
straight steering mix just to
demonstrate what your car what would
your car your car will perform as
compared to this if you if you follow
the same instructions uh the other
things other than that nothing special
the top block I have is 2.5
yes the shock itself there is shocks
for the standard xrx the shocks that
come with it the rear one is very stiff
for me so I went for this shocks which I
stole from one of my son's toy cars and
it's a little bit it's not soft it's
medium
if you want to to buy it I think it's
it's very comparable to the medium shots
that you get with the
with the DK
electronic wise I'm running the the
standard a11 CLS servo
I'm running the V2 gyro
surpass hobby which is very cheap 12 or
14 dollars I'm not sure 6000 KV and I
geared up more this time this is 26
tooth Pena I have the standard atomic
sensorless ESC uh adjusted the punch
value is adjusted to one as we talked
about and other than that
oh right height
my right height
back
two millimeter
front 2.5 millimeter so my chassis is
leaning backwards I'm not sure if I can
if you can grab this camera
and I'm going for a high most romantic
position if you are a beginner don't
install your Mount your motor down below
the reason for that because I want to
test this combination of
throttle curve and uh gearing up and
punch zero Punch or low punch to see if
I can control the car like this the
higher motor mount position requires
more throttle control it's more suitable
if you have a sensored system and it's
more suitable if you have any previous
experience when it comes to Drifting as
general regarding wheel alignment I'm
running rear zero camber
front
three degrees camber I'm running almost
parallel steering you can see it here
this it looks like a towel it's not too
hot because when you squat the car
it will almost end up
a sparrow steering or pair Ackerman and
other than that my Caster is Max all my
spacers are up front here if you can see
so the arms are pushed all the way back
and we'll see how that performs
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
there you go guys that's almost almost
all I know regarding this Hobby I
remember when I started up I used to bug
Beaver all the time with questions
all the time and he was kind enough to
answer all of them and I'm trying to do
the same here share whatever I know with
you if you are a beginner just ask man
there's no shame in that there are no
such thing as stupid questions asked and
we will try as a group we will try to
answer you to our best ability
sometimes I I come across
a threat that I don't react to the
reason for that mostly is either um I
don't know the answer to that question
or I don't own that chassis so I don't
want to speak about something that I've
never tried or or drifted I don't want
to spread any false information but if
if the question regarding something I
own or something I tried I I usually
answer it immediately if you are an old
Drifter regarding all Drifters guys stop
being [ __ ] toward newcomers
share the information guys share the
share the love
this
is not something that you can prove your
manhood over
stop killing the hobby help one another
and I hope this video helps you with
your build in some shape or form and
with that being said Peace